Ted Barclay Correspondence WLU.Coll.0002
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Ted Barclay Correspondence
1861-1864
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
WLU.Coll.0002
.4 Linear Feet
Online Access
View this collection online in W&L's Digital Archive
Biographical / Historical
Ted Barclay was a Lexington, Virginia native and a member of Washington College (later known as Washington and Lee University) Class of 1861. He then served in the Liberty Hall Volunteers of the Stonewall Brigade (4th Infantry) for the Confederate Army during the American Civil War (1861-1864) and later was a trustee of Washington and Lee University.
Scope and Contents
Includes autographed letters signed and typed copies of Barclay's letters to his family in Lexington, Virginia during the American Civil War. The letters include: information about the activities of the Liberty Hall Volunteers of the Stonewall Brigade in major battles within Virginia; accounts of life in Confederate camp; information about food, clothing, diseases, religious services, attractive women, and deaths of friends while serving with the Volunteers; and accounts of his life as a Union prisoner at Fort Delaware. These letters have been published in a volume edited by Charles Turner, Ted Barclay, Liberty Hall Volunteers: Letters from the Stonewall Brigade (1861-1864).
Delaware -- Fort Delaware; Correspondence; Cookery, Military; Armies -- Military life; Armies -- Religious life; History; Virginia; Prisoners of war; Barclay, Ted, II (Alexander Tedford)
- Control folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1861-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-06-10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1861-06-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-06-14 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-06-22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay and Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-06-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1861-07-1861-08 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-07-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-07-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1861-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1861-12-01 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1861-12-06 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1861-12-23 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1862-02 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-02-01 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-02-05 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-02-10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-02-19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-02-22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1862-03-1862-04 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-03-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-03-31 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-04-15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1862-05 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-05-16 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-05-26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-05-27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1862-05-29 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1863-06 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-06-03 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-06-17 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-06-19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1863-07 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-07-08 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-07-13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-07-14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-07-20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-07-24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1863-08-1863-09 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-08-03 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1863-08-05 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1863-08-17 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-09-01 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-09-16 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-09-29 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1863-10-1863-11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-10-13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-10-21 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-10-24 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-11-10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-11-15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-11-19 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-11-25 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1863-12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-12-05 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1863-12-29 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1864-01-1864-03 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-01-26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Homefolks (Hannah Moore Barclay and Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay), 1864-02-10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-02-22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-03-02 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-03-09 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-03-12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-03-21 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1864-06-1864-08 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-06-07 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ted Barclay to Mary Elanor Paxton Barclay, 1864-07-21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ted Barclay to Hannah Moore Barclay, 1864-08-21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence (typescripts), 1861-1864 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Duplicate Correspondence, 1861-1864 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous notes of Professor W. G. Bean, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Photograph of Barclay, no date
- Duplicate Correspondence, no date